BESBES OUSSEMA

ICT ENGINEERING STUDENT

PROFILE SUMMARY

Second year ICT engineering student at the Higher School of Communication of Tunis(SUP'COM), I have demonstrated the ability to adapt to both self-starting and collaborative environments, with a growing interest and experience in DevOps practices.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Programming Languages:

- Python/C/C++
- HTML/CSS/Java script

SGBD:

• Mongodb/Mysql

Frameworks:

Reactjs/Nodejs

Containerization:

Docker/Kubernetes

DevOps tools:

- AWS
- Jenkins
- Anisble

EDUCATION

Higher school of communication of Tunis (SUP'COM)

Sep 2021 -Present

Preparatory institue for engineering studies of Sfax (IPEIS)

Sep 2019 -June 2021

RANK:108 Mathematics & Physics

Mongi Slim secondary school

Mathematics Baccalaureate

Sep 2016 -June 2019

PROJECTS

Projet de métier(P2M)

Jan 2023 - June 2023

Continuous integration and continuous deployment Project

- Developed and designed an micro-services auction website.
- Implemented automated CI/CD pipelines on Jenkins running on EC2.
- Created Helm charts to enable easy deployment of the microservices to Kubernetes.
- Utilized ingress and nginx to explose the microservices to external traffic.
- Extended unit testing and best practices with Jest and Selenuim

Keywords: AWS, Github, Jenkins, DockerHub, Kubernetes, Helm, ingress, nginx, Linode, Jest, Selenuim, MySQL, NodeJS, ReactJS, Socket, JWT.

Created a basic application and successfully deployed it on an EC2 instance using Docker.also set up a Jenkins pipeline to automate the deployment process. Keywords:AWS,Github,webhooks,Nodejs,MySQL,Reactjs,jest,Dockerhub

EXPERIENCE

IT INTERN Jul 2022- Aug 2022

Coode Cooperation



CodeCooperation designs, builds and manages software from the heart of Berlin and Tunis. Developed and designed an micro-services auction website.

 Design and development of a web application for human resource management that allows viewing all projects, the progress status of each project and task, and also enables leave requests.

Keywords: Reactjs, Nestjs, Mongodb, API consuming, Swagger, Heroku, Jira

Jul 2023- Aug 2023

Sofrecom Sfax



As a subsidiary of the Orange Group, Sofrecom is a consulting and engineering firm specializing in telecommunications.

- Setting up a portal that enables the investigative center to request patient consent for one or multiple clinical studies.
- Designing the portal and its various interfaces.
- Developing various use cases.

Keywords: Reactjs, Nodejs, Mysql, PhpMyAdmin, API consuming, Bloackchain , Docker